Hi, I'm Heather. I am a 36-year-old wife, mother of four adult children, and
three grand babies. I have been married to my husband for 36 years.
We are high school sweethearts, so we've actually been together for 40 years.
like I said, four adult children. Only one of them lives near me, the
other three live off. And my grand babies are 18 months, 9 months, and
2 months old. So pretty young. they're coming fast. before Strong Standard, I would
say that I was ... yes, a mother, so a lot of things get
put on the back burners to take care of your kids, even adult children.
Wanting to be there, be a part of their lives, be involved as much
as I can. so yes, some of that. A busy mom who just put
herself last. And also, I wanna say, just very frustrated and lazy.
I wanted it to come easy. I really desired to be healthy and fit and look
good and feel good and all the things, but wasn't really willing to put
the work in that it took to do it. And, did at times but
not at times. And just frustrated in general at, at the whole process and,
and giving up and just gotten lazy. what did my life look like at
my lowest point? I would say that actually has come pretty recently, my lowest
point did. my Really was just, I wanna say, uncomfortable. It wasn't that I
didn't do things that I wanted to do. I still pushed through and did
a lot of things. I did a lot of things that I wanted to
say no to because either I didn't physically feel like doing it, or I
was uncomfortable the way I looked doing it. But I would still say yes,
because if it was something that I could do that allowed me to be
a part of my kids' lives, I was gonna say yes to it no
matter what. But would spend a lot of time... So some examples of that
would be, my daughter lives in Florida, and we also have a place on
the lake. So the favorite
place for my family together when we get together is at the lake, where
lake activities are on boats, in swimsuits, in the water, that kind of thing.
And, and then just the activity of that many people together. I have two
children that are married, two that are serious dating. Anyway, so I didn't really
say no to things, but I got to where I started dreading them, and
I hated that. I didn't wanna dread when my family was gonna get together,
or I was gonna get to spend time with my kids. But I would.
I would dread it because I would either feel like this is gonna just
make me so exhausted and so tired, or I'm gonna have to do things
that I feel uncomfortable doing, either physically or... physically, as far as, they would
be hard for me to do physically, or physically as in I just didn't
like the way I looked. I was uncomfortable in the clothes that I would
need to wear. When it's, when you're at the lake and it's summertime and
it's hot, you're in clothes that are more revealing, or in a swimsuit.
And, I would, one, just be
physically uncomfortable in them. They would be too tight, or they just didn't fit
right, and... Or I didn't like the way it looked on me, or it
made me look even bigger than I already was. and then also just super
self-conscious. And so I'm wanting to have fun with my family, but I'm...
In the back of my mind is this feeling of just I don't look
good. I don't feel good. I hate that I'm this exposed. so very self-conscious,
very uncomfortable in that point of view, in that way. so as much mentally
and emotionally it was hard as it was physically, Things that I had tried
before. Huh, the gamut, right? I feel like there's so many things.
I don't even know if any of y'all are old enough to remember the
cabbage soup diet, but there was a time, oh, way back when, I did
the cabbage soup diet. I think I only did it for two days, because
one, it was terrible, and two, I knew that it wasn't very healthy, and
so I didn't keep up with it. but have tried different fad diets before.
High, Atkins diet, low,
super low carbs, Weight Watchers, "Oh, I'm just gonna cut out these things."
the more recently probably would be just, "I just won't eat much of anything
until dinner time, and then I can just have a decent dinner or the
dinner that I want." so I guess I'm gonna call that the starvation diet,
'cause I was starving during the day. and some of those programs, y'all, I'm
not saying are bad. Weight Watchers I think has been... I know people who
did it, were successful at it, and have maintained a healthy weight and lifestyle
since they tried it. So I don't really wanna knock any particular program like
that. I would just say for me, I would get on them.
some of them didn't last a week, some of them might last a month,
some of them lasted several months, and I had some success in them, but
they never lasted long term. Eventually, I stopped doing it for various reasons.
mainly just because I, they just weren't maintainable for me. And, even the ones that I
think might be good for some people that weren't good for me, they weren't
good for me because it was here's our program, you fit yourself into our
program. And I would try it, and then, but it wouldn't work.
It wouldn't work long term. Would it work for a little while?
Sure, and I would have a little some success, but then it would just
get overwhelming, and I would get tired and frustrated with it and give it
up. I think that was the biggest thing. either that was just so extreme
that hardly anybody's ever gonna maintain that, or it was me having to adapt
to their program and me not finding the program that I could adapt myself
to long term. what finally made me try again, a specific moment.
I'm not gonna say I had an exact set moment. I had several things
that kinda compounded all at once. One was my spouse, in the nicest, gentlest,
kindest way saying, I'd like for you to do something." which he had said for years.
and me finally getting past the point of being angry with him and looking
at it from his perspective, and that took a long time to get there.
The other was I do regularly go to the doctor for checkups, and blood
work, and all that kinda stuff, and I had probably had the worst checkup
I had ever had, and it was the first time that she really got
serious and talked to me "Okay, we're... something needs to happen here because you're
trending in a direction that's not good, and we don't wanna go there."
that compounded with I did just have, at this point, two grand babies and
one on the way, and realizing that I have four children. These are not
gonna be my only grandkids. I could be having grandkids for another six, seven,
10 years. I could still be having... people have grand babies or people have
babies, and I wanna be here for that, and I wanna be able to
be fully involved in them. If they wanna go play kickball in the front
yard, which I did a zillion times with my kids and don't really like
it, but I did I wanna be able to go do that. if
they wanna go to Six Flags for the day and they want me to
come with them, I wanna be able to hang with them. so physically, as
far as I wanna be able to walk, and do those things, and not
have aches and pains, and knee problems, or elbow, whatever. but also just physically
with my health. If I've got bad health issues, those things are gonna be
limited. And it was almost like I've got a second, third life starting over
again, and I wanna be there and be present for it, and be healthy
for it. along with that was I've, I knew it. I've known this all
along. I finally accepted it, is this is a lifestyle change. We hear that
term all the time. I knew the term. I'd heard it before.
I knew what it was. I didn't wanna accept that it was that for
me. no, I'm just gonna do this for a little while, but I'm not
gonna have to change my life for the rest of my life.
this isn't gonna be for the rest of my life. It's just gonna be
for a little while. And, I finally accepted this is gonna be for the
rest of my life. That being said, you've
gotta do what you can do for the rest of your life.
I can't do what Jim Bob over here can do. I'm not gonna be
an Rx CrossFitter, and I'm not gonna eat cauliflower crust pizza every time I
eat I'm just not gonna go that extreme. Cauliflower crust might be a bad
example, but you get what I'm saying. Like these extreme, I can't have any
kind of real fat, and I can't have any kind of sugar unless it's
sugar from fruit, and I can't have, I... That's just too extreme for me.
I'm not gonna do that. There is some life that needs to be enjoyed.
anyway, realizing that I think I need to say this before I get into
the next part about strong standard, Finally accepting that this was a lifestyle change
meant that I had to really find what was gonna work. Excuse me.
And I was so discouraged. I was so down in the dumps.
I spent weeks just in a really big funk because I knew I needed
to make a change, and I didn't know how in the world I was
gonna do it. And I knew that
everything I had tried before hadn't worked, and there's so much information out there,
and I feel like at least 80% of it is false and not good.
And, I just felt at a loss of, I know this is what I
need to do. I'm ready to do this, but I have no clue how.
And, talk about frustration and ready to kinda give up. And, but also I'm
"I'm 56. I have so much more life ahead of me. I can't give
up. What am I gonna do?" And then I found Strong Standard randomly because
there was another fitness guy that I follow who has a podcast.
I don't even listen to podcasts regularly, but I listened to this.
I'm a Christian, so I'm gonna say this was God designed. I listened to
this podcast that had Joey on it, and I just loved everything that he
had to say. Because, one, he was formally educated, but he also wasn't...
He also was willing to say everybody physical body is different. And so we
can't approach nutrition and exercise and everything the same for everybody because
people aren't the same. And I love that he had some knowledge and interest
in things that we're learning about nutrition and education and stuff today, but also
not going deep diving off on this, whatever the latest trend is in the
nutrition industry. But the thing that really stuck out to me the most was
when he talked about his particular program, he said, "We fit the program to
you. We don't fit you to our program." I don't think those were his
exact words, but that's what he was saying. And that perked up.
That made me perk up 'cause I thought, "Okay. One..." Excuse me, I have
to take a drink One, I feel like he's got some education here.
He's not coming just from he had some years of personal experience, but he
also had some education. So those two together, and I just loved the, "Hey,
I, I wanna work with you, and I wanna say, 'Okay, you can't...
You don't have an hour and a half to go spend in the gym
every day, so let's figure out what you can do.'" Loved that, and that
was the biggest, that was, the next question is what does Strong
Standard do differently than everybody else or everything else, and that was the main
thing is you're working with me. And I will say, at first when I
started it, I was hesitant to... Ceci Ceci is my coach. I was hesitant
to, sometimes express things "I don't think I like doing that," or, "I don't
really wanna do that," or, "I'm not gonna do that," because I felt like
I was, a two-year-old kinda stomping her foot saying, "I'm not gonna do that,"
and I just needed to suck it up and do it. But I have
learned through the process that I need to express to her, "Hey, this is
just something I'm never gonna do, and I know that." I don't like smoothies,
so a great way to get protein is to drink a smoothie and add
your protein to the smoothie and all that. That's not gonna work for me.
I don't like them. I'm not gonna do it. So how else can I
get my protein in for the day? and she was just so great about
that. She was so great about working with me. when I finally started kinda
being more vocal about things, she was so encouraging. "Please tell me.
These are the things I've been needing you to tell me so that we can
work together, so we can figure out what will work for you.
How can I make this better?" she's she's so introspective. She's so great at,
I do my check-ins and I say things and I feel like I really
didn't give that much information, and she comes back with all kinds of stuff
that I'm "I didn't realize I was telling you those things." But so good
at kinda deep diving into, "Okay, I get a sense that this is not
good for you," or, "This isn't working," or whatever. so just that alone, just
being able to say, "Hey, I did this. I tried this, and I did
it okay for a couple weeks. I did pretty good with it, but I
know I'm not gonna maintain this for long term. So can we adjust it
somehow? Can we figure out a different way that might work for me because
I'm not gonna be, I'm not gonna be able to do that."
Great. She's great at doing that, great at adapting for me, my lifestyle, my
likes, my dislikes, my, all those things. and then the other thing is absolutely
no guilt. She's never one time made me feel bad when I didn't do
it perfectly, and, that's been encouraging too because
life isn't perfect and I'm not gonna do it perfectly, and I have felt
in the past "Well, you're on this program and you've gotta do this program,
and don't, Oh, you messed up this one day and you got off the
program, and now you've just messed up everything." And, that was frustrating because life
is not that way, and my life is the least scheduled and the same
every week than it has ever been, ever. I am out of town a
great deal. and so she's really been good about being able to work with
me on all those aspects, and not make me feel guilty when I didn't
do it perfect. Actually encouraged and just said, "Hey, I love that you didn't
do it perfect this week, but you have a great attitude because you didn't
get discouraged and say you wanted to quit. You just said, 'Okay, I didn't
do it perfect this week. These were some things that were stumbling blocks.
How can I keep those stumbling blocks from happening?'" Or, "These are some stumbling
blocks that are gonna happen pretty regularly. What am I gonna do?
How am I gonna live with that and still stay on a healthy program?"
I hate using the word program, too,
because I feel like program isn't really what it is. But I don't have
another word, what's the hardest moment during the process? I would say one is,
being fully honest, and that was just a me thing. But that was hard
for me, being fully honest with what I felt about different things that we're,
we were doing, trying, talking about, that kind of thing. weight training in general.
I don't love to work out. I have always done some form of, some
type of exercise. I've obviously added a little bit to it. I don't love
doing it and I don't love the time it takes, so that's been difficult.
But she's working with me on that, too, and we're figuring out ways to,
make it more enjoyable and doable. And then, Really, I think for me, the
hardest sometimes is getting back on the wagon. So maybe I was out of
town for a weekend, and I had a day or two where I just
kinda stepped back from everything and didn't worry or didn't, have a good mindset
about thinking about what am I eating or what am I doing, or am
I gonna get my walks in or whatever. so sometimes if I've
had a day or two that I've just not done real great, and I
would say like my adherence to everything was maybe a five, then sometimes getting
back at it the next day, sometimes that's a struggle. But, but as far
as Strong Standards process, what's been the most difficult, it's really been not that
difficult, and that's the thing that's been so surprising to me. I've said it
to Ceci so many times. This is just so doable. to ask about my
I have the worst time saying this word. My satiety level has been, it's
been great. I haven't really been hungry. I've done what they've asked me to
do, and I haven't been hungry. So I think the hardest maybe is, again,
being completely honest with her, being willing to say, "This does or doesn't work
for me." And then I would say also too, just trusting the process, because,
it's a while before you actually get into the weight loss phase.
And so just trusting what they're telling you, trusting the whole process, giving it
a try, working it out, and, and being
patient with results down the road. what can I do now that I couldn't
or wouldn't do before? I feel like I need to say this first.
I am only about halfway through my first weight loss phase. I've only been
doing this about four months. So I'm not as far along as maybe some
people are to be able to say, "Oh, six months in, a year in,
a year and a half in, this is where I am." I'm not that
far, but I can tell you where I am at this moment in the
stage that I'm in now. I already feel a difference just physically, like my
energy level. I noticed the other day I did something and I was "Oh
wait, that was easy." I didn't have to think about, oh, I'm gonna use
getting off the floor as an example. I can't remember what it was.
But anyway, I am up and down off the floor a lot 'cause I
keep one of my grand babies three days a week. And, just things with
him, picking him up, getting him out of things, getting up off the floor,
all that kind of stuff is getting a little bit easier. And I feel
like my weight, workouts aren't super intense and so it... I'm was a little
surprised that I'm already
seeing that big of... That difference in that. So physically, and just physically in
general, I just feel better, and I know that I'm making better choices with
my food in quantity, quality, all of that, and I can feel the difference.
I'm beginning to see the difference, but most importantly, I feel the difference.
And that's... The seeing is gonna come, and that's gonna be a little bit
slower, I think, down, getting there. But when you feel so much better, then
it just makes it easier to keep going because you know what you're doing
is good. things that I'm better at doing, I think, or I couldn't say
couldn't or wouldn't, 'cause like I said before, there really wasn't that much that
I wouldn't do. But I would say I am much better about managing my
food when I am out of town, and I am out of town a
great deal. So it used to be anytime I went out of town was
just an excuse to just go out to eat and eat whatever I wanted
to, 'cause I'm out of town, I'm at a restaurant, And, it's become so
much easier to make good choices and still
enjoy what I'm eating, still have, still splurge a little bit here and there.
But all in all, make better choices. And because I'm feeling satisfied and not
hungry and not, limiting myself in such strong ways that I'm just wanna pig
out when I go out to eat, it's made making good choices so much
easier and pleasant and enjoyable. I'm gonna use that word, even enjoyable.
So I love that. and then again, just more energy, more strength all the
way around. It's been awesome. my spouse is the one who's noticed first, of
course. They would be the one I haven't lost a significant amount of weight
yet that I think many people have noticed, or at least noticed to the
point where they're saying something. But, but definitely my spouse has noticed, all the
way around. Just noticed that it seems to be easier for me than it's
been in the past, noticed that I am losing some weight, noticed that I
have more energy, all those things. So that's encouraging too, when someone else sees it. I
would say before I was frustrated, discouraged, discouraged. That was my biggest word.
I was just so discouraged. And now I have, I'm encouraged, I have hope,
I have ambition, determination, resolve, and those things, I needed some of those when
I got started, but they've just been reinforced because this program is working, and
it's working because we're making it work for me and my lifestyle.
oh gosh, if somebody's watching this that feels like I did, I would just
say give it a try. Give it a try. Go in wholeheartedly, 100%, give
it a try. Trust the process, trust what they're telling you to do, and
give it a try. Because I, again, I'm four months in, so I would
love to be able to do this again when I'm a year and a
half or two years in, I can foresee what my answer's gonna be.
It was so worth it. It was so worth it to, finally get something that actually
worked for me. And, I'm so thankful for it in so many ways.
and I'm continuing to trust the process 'cause I've still got some work to
do and I've still got a little ways to go. But, but I don't
have any fear or interpretation about the next step or whatever else comes next
because I know we're gonna work through it and we're gonna figure out what
works, and then we're gonna do it. So that's it.